<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<letter>
    <pageMark num="6"/>
    <p>
        <s>We may observe daily, without going from home, that those who have least <replaced
                style="crossedOut">disposition</replaced> to acquire by active exertion are
            generally the most greedy to obtain by other means even although they should not be the
            most honorable.</s>
        <s> Active industry appears rather to be an antidote to avarice and <added how="carrot"
                unintelligable="yes"/> an incitement to generosity.</s>
        <s> The successful hunter has <added how="margins" aligned="above">for the most part</added>
            been found generous; and why, might we not hope, should we become herdsmen, or farmers
            (for we cannot expect to be able to reanimate the bones of the departed inhabitants of
            our forests) that he, who has had success with his flock or his crop, would also be
            generous of that which the bountiful hand of nature had bestowed on him, as a reward for
            his labor and <added how="carrot">his</added> care.</s>
        <s>
            <added how="margins" alighed="sidewaysLeft">There is besides a further satisfaction in
                this kind of employment, that success in it depends more on our own conduct than it
                does in that of the hunter.</added>
        </s>
    </p>

    <p>
        <s> I apprehend <person who="recipient">my Dear friend</person>, that there is hardly any
            si-tuation more exposed to the baneful<removed unintelligible="yes" style="crossedOut"/>
            vices of covetousness, and envy than that of our particular Five Tribes.</s>
        <removed untillegible="yes" style="crossedOut"/>
        <s>Situate, as they are, in the neighborhood of and among European settlements, their wants
            to become greater than their industry can supply; for the hunter, however fortunate he
            may be, cannot at present obtain sufficient peltries to purchase wherewithal to cloth a
            family amply.</s>
        <s> Our farming supplies little more than sufficient for our own consumption.</s>
        <s>
            <replaced style="crossedOut">What remains</replaced>
            <added how="margins" aligned="left">consists of</added> the pitiful annuities at two or
            three dollars per man.</s>
        <s>Then the bounty of our Father the King is a great support to such as are in favor with
            the <person>Superintendent</person>; but I fear that <added how="carrot" aligned="above"
                >in order</added> to enjoy this favor, some are tempted to be mean.</s>
        <s> To pursue industrious employment with judgement would be much better than all those.</s>
        <s> For instance, twenty dollars wherewith you may buy a cow and, with care, may every year
            raise a calf, will be of more service to your family for the present time than three
            dollars annuity; besides, that at the end of ten years, you may have a considerable
            stock of cattle.</s>
    </p>

    <p>
        <s cutOff="start">
            <obscured pattern="lines">Indeed there is nothing to prevent us in some degree from
                imitating the Industry of Europeans, but the <added how="carrot" aligned="above"
                    >want of</added> Will you will say, they are rich, and we are poor; but riches
                are of no utility in this respect, but as they command the labor of many, and direct
                their joined efforts to</obscured>
        </s>
        <pageMark n="7"/>
        <obscured pattern="bleedThrough">
            <s cutOff="finished">a general point.</s>
            <s>By union a number of men may perform the same labor <added how="carrot"
                    aligned="above">which</added> a single rich man does by means of his money.</s>
            <s>In war it has been the custom for our warriors to unite firmly together to support
                the honor of our tribes and to destroy the human species. </s>
            <s cutOff="start">In peace can we not as well</s>
        </obscured>
        <s cutOff="finish"> unite our joint efforts for the preservation and increase of our
            species, by rendering them comfortable in the abundant supply of all their <replaced
                style="crossedOut">natural</replaced> wants<added how="insertion" aligned="after"
                >?</added></s>
        <s>You will yet observe that we are in want of the necessary implements and utensils for
            carrying on work extensively<added how="insertion" aligned="after">:</added> this is
            very true; but when difficulties occur in a laudable attempt, we must not for that
            season desist, but <added how="carrot" aligned="above">rather</added> endeavor to remedy
            them as well as we can.</s>
        <s>For instance, could we prevail on the people to be content for one year with two dollars
            instead of three in the division of the annuities, this might contribute considerably
            towards the furnishing these athidy<added how="insertion" aligned="after">:</added> and
            as sometimes a warrior who has been obliged to go to war without any other weapon but a
            spear becomes possessed of a gun from some of his conquered enemies; so if you persevere
            like men, finally the fruits of your labors will furnish all<removed unintelligible="yes"
                style="crossedOut"/>that is wanted.</s>
    </p>

    <p>
        <s>I arrive in <place>Utica</place> at dusk, and find that the stage leaves it at daybreak.
            Next day I enter it in company with a single gentleman in black; we have a very silent
            ride, the great fall of snow causing us to go on very slowly and ar-rive in the evening
            at the <place>Stone Church</place>. <place>The Inn</place> where we put up was formerly
            the house of our old friend <person>Major Nellis</person>: the present landlord retains
            a strong remembrance of last war; and perhaps on that account, and the dress I was in
            did not give me that reception which it was his duty to do, a circumstance which caused
            me to be the more particular.</s>
        <removed style="crossedOut" unintelligible="yes"/>
        <page num="6"/>
        <s>
            <added how="carrot" aligned="above">In the morning</added> we again embarked, there were
            now two additional gentlemen in company.</s>
        <s>One of these gentlemen being of a social communicative temper we became very well
            acquainted before we <replaced style="crossedOut" aligned="above">reached</replaced>
            <place>Schenectady</place> where we dined, and arrived about ten o’ clock last night at
            this place.</s>
        <s> I put up with one of my companions at the city tavern, where we find <person>Lord
                Selkirk</person> a <added how="carrot" aligned="above">very respectable</added>
            Scotch nobleman who has had allotted to him in the western half of Canada a tract of
            land to be settled by people from <place>Scotland</place>, whom an over-crowded
            population compels to emigrate; and, as I have heard before I left you, His Lordship
            benevolently gives them his aid to bring them over &amp; <added how="carrot"
                aligned="above">enable them </added>to establish them-selves there; This nobleman is
            exceedingly pleasant, affable, &amp; intelligent I had the pleasure of a considerable
            conver-sation with him probably from his desire of being made acquainted <added
                how="carrpt" aligned="above">with the manners &amp; customs of</added> our people
            and their connections.</s>
        <s>I have seen several of the great men here but had not time to see the Governor. </s>
        <s>I had proposed stopping within this evening, it being wet and disagreeable out; but I
            find Mr. R <replaced style="crossedOut" unintelligible="yes">sends</replaced> to let me
                <added how="carrot" aligned="above">know</added> that supper is ready so I must
                <replaced unintelligible="yes" style="crossedOut">set</replaced> off. </s>
        <s>
            <signOff>– Adieu my dear friend</signOff>
        </s>
        <obscured pattern="lines bleedThrough"/>
    </p>

</letter>
