<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="recipeSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<recipe>
    <information>
        <title>Shrewsbury Cakes: Original Recipe. </title>
        <context> This recipe comes from MS Codex 625, a manuscript recipe book that belonged to a
            student in a London cooking school in the early eighteenth century. The pastry school
            was owned by Edward Kidder, who taught at a few locations in London between around <year>1720</year>
            and <year>1734</year>. Blank books with printed title pages seem to have been used by students to
            write down recipes they learned. Kidder also published his recipes in the printed
            volume, Receipts for Pastry and Cookery, in <year>1720</year>. </context>
    </information>

    <original>
        <step> Take <ing>
                <quant>a pound</quant> of fresh butter </ing>
            <ing>
                <quant>a pound</quant> of <state>double refind</state> sugar <state>sifted fine
                </state>
            </ing>
            <ing>
                <quant>a little</quant>
                <state>beaten</state> mace </ing>
            <ing> &amp; <quant>4</quant> eggs </ing> beat them all together with. your hands till
            tis very leight &amp; looks curdling </step>

        <step> you put thereto <ing>
                <quant>a pound &amp; 1/2</quant> of flower </ing> roul them out into little cakes
        </step>
    </original>

    <additional>
        <section>
            <title>Our recipe </title>
            <comment>(halved from the original)</comment>
            <listed>
                <ingList what="butter" amnt="1.5" measure="lb"/>
                <ingList what="sugar" amnt="1.5" measure="lb" state="softened"/>
                <ingList what="mace" amnt=".25" measure="tsp"/>
                <ingList what="cinnamon" amnt=".5" measure="tsp"/>
                <ingList what="eggs" amnt="2" measure="item"/>
                <ingList what="flour" amnt=".75" measure="lb"/>
            </listed>

            <newStep>Using an electric mixer, cream together the <ing>butter</ing> and
                <ing>sugar</ing>.</newStep>
            <newStep>Then add the <ing>eggs</ing> and mix at medium speed until the mixture looks
                    <state>curdled</state>.</newStep>
            <newStep>Sift together dry ingredients and add at low speed until just
                    <state>combined</state>.</newStep>
            <newStep>Scoop and roll the <ing>dough</ing> by hand into <quant>1-tbsp</quant>. balls,
                then pat <state>flat</state>.</newStep>
            <newStep type="optional">[You could also refrigerate the dough until it’s firm enough to
                roll out on a flat surface and cut out into rounds.]</newStep>


            <newStep>
                <bake tempF="350" duration="15 to 18" timeframe="minutes"/>
                <comment>(ours were about 1/3″ thick, so you could roll them thinner and have a
                    slightly shorter cooking time).</comment>
            </newStep>
            <comment>They’re done once they turn the slightest bit brown around the edges. This
                halved recipe yielded about two dozen cookies.</comment>
        </section>
        <section>
            <title>The Results </title>
            <comment>If you like snickerdoodles (and who doesn’t?), you’d like these. We added the
                    <ing>cinnamon</ing> because we like it and couldn’t resist, and we thought it
                rounded out the <ing>mace</ing> nicely. These are mild, fairly soft cookies that are
                great with tea. We rolled and patted the dough into individual cookies because it
                was too soft and stick to roll out, but a little bit more <ing>flour</ing> and a
                stint in the fridge might make the dough easier to work with a rolling
                pin.</comment>
        </section>
    </additional>
</recipe>
